meetup.com 2017-12-07

# Privacy Policy

Our Privacy Policy explains how information about you is collected, used, and disclosed by Meetup. The terms “Meetup,” “we,” “us,” and “our” include Meetup Inc. and our affiliates. This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect when you use our “Platform”, which means any website, application, or service we offer, or when you communicate with us. For information about choices we offer under this policy, please see “Your Choices” below. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the information you may provide to third parties, such as members of Meetup, and others with whom you may share information about you. For more information about the scope of our Privacy Policy, please see Section 4.8 below.

To make this Privacy Policy easier to understand, we have provided summaries in these gray boxes. These summaries are not part of the official policy. Even though we have provided summaries, it is important for you to read the entire policy carefully.

## 1\. Collection of Information

Summary: We collect information about you when you: 

  * create an account;
  * use the Platform; and
  * communicate with us.

We also collect information, such as usage statistics, by using cookies, server logs, and similar technologies.

If you elect to use certain features, we also collect information through other sources, such as social media services, invitations, and imported contacts.

1.1 Information You Provide to Us

We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information you provide when you create an account, fill out a form, or communicate with us. The types of information we may collect include your name, email address, postal address, phone number, payment method data, photos, and any other information you choose to provide.

1.2 Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Platform 

When you use our Platform, we automatically collect information about you, including:

  * Log Information: We collect log information about your use of the Platform, including the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address, and the page you visited before visiting our Platform.
  * Device Information: We collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access our Platform, including the hardware model, operating system and version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information.
  * Location Information: We may collect information about the location of your device each time you use our Platform, or when you otherwise consent to the collection of this information.
  * Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies: We and our service providers collect information using various technologies, including cookies and pixel tags (which are also called clear GIFs, web beacons, or pixels). Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us improve our Platform and your experience, and track usage of our Platform. Pixel tags are electronic images that may be used in our Platform or emails, and track usage of our Platform and effectiveness of communications. You can learn more about the types of cookies we and our service providers use by reading our [Cookie Policy](https://www.meetup.com/cookie_policy/). 
  * Other Information: With your permission, we may collect other information from your device, such as photos from your camera roll, contacts of individuals you wish to find or connect with, or calendar information you want to manage via the Platform. 

1.3 Information We Collect From Other Sources 

We may collect information about you from other sources, such as through certain features on the Platform you elect to use, including:

  * Social Media Services. If you register or log into your account through a third-party social media service, we will have access to some of your third-party account information from that service, such as your name and other information in that account, as authorized by that service. You have the ability to disable the connection between our Platform and your third-party account at any time.
  * Invitations. If another member sends you an invitation through our Platform, we may receive your email address or phone number. If you are an invited guest, we will automatically send you an invitation to our Platform, and, if unanswered, a one-time follow-up invitation. Meetup stores this contact information only to send these invitations and evaluate their success. You may unsubscribe from future invitations using the instructions in those messages. You may also contact us at [support@meetup.com](mailto:support@meetup.com) to request that we remove this information from our database. 

## 2\. Use of Information

Summary: We use information about you to: 

  * operate, improve, promote, and protect Meetup and our Platform;
  * communicate with you; and
  * personalize content.

2.1 Operating our Platform

We may use information about you for various purposes related to operating our Platform, including to:

  1. Provide, maintain, and improve our Platform, including to process transactions, and develop new products and services;
  2. Personalize the Platform;
  3. Monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with our Platform;
  4. Detect, investigate, and prevent fraudulent transactions, abuse, and other illegal activities, and protect the rights property, or safety of Meetup and others;

2.2 Communicating with You

We may use information about you for various purposes related to communicating with you, including to:

  1. Respond to your comments, questions, and requests, and provide customer service;
  2. Communicate with you about products, services, and events offered by us and others, and provide news and information we think will be of interest to you;
  3. Deliver communications from other members, in accordance with the communication preferences that you indicate in your account;
  4. Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts and support, and administrative messages;

2.3 Advertising and Other Uses

We may use information about you for various other purposes, including to:

  1. Provide advertisements, content, or features that match member profiles or interests;
  2. Facilitate contests and other promotions;
  3. Combine with information we collect for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy; and
  4. Carry out any other purposes described to you at the time the information was collected.

## 3\. Sharing of Information

Summary: We do not share information about you in any way other than as described in this Privacy Policy or with your consent. 

We may disclose information about you:

  * to members or social media services, subject to the choices you may make via the Platform;
  * to our third-party service providers that help us to operate or improve our Platform;
  * to authorities to comply with legal obligations and to protect and defend our rights and property; and
  * to an affiliate or successor entity as part of a corporate transaction.

We may also share de-identified or aggregated information.

3.1 Through our Platform

We share some of the information we collect by displaying it on our Platform according to your member profile and account settings. Some information, such as user name, is always public. Some information, such as interests, is public by default but can be hidden on our Platform. Some information, such as group memberships, will always be visible to other members of that Meetup group, and may be public, depending on the settings of that group. For more information, see this [FAQ on Account Privacy and Visibility](https://www.meetup.com/help/article/864924/). 

3.2 With Our Service Providers

We may use service providers in connection with operating and improving the Platform to assist with certain functions, such as payment processing, email transmission, conducting surveys or contests, data hosting, managing our ads, and some aspects of our technical and customer support. We take measures to ensure that these service providers access, process and store information about you only for the purposes we authorize, subject to confidentiality obligations.

3.3 Following the Law and Protecting Meetup

We may access, preserve, and disclose to third parties information about you if we believe disclosure is in accordance with, or required by, applicable law, regulation or legal process. We may also disclose information about you if we believe that your actions are inconsistent with our [Terms of Service](https://www.meetup.com/terms/) or related guidelines and policies, or if necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of, or prevent fraud or abuse of, Meetup or others. 

3.4 Social Sharing and Other Tools

The Platform may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools which let you share actions you take on our Platform with third-party services, and vice versa. Such features let you share information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you have chosen with the service. The service’s use of the information will be governed by their privacy policies, and we do not control their use of the shared data. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please review the privacy policies of the services that provide these features.

3.5 Affiliate Sharing and Merger, Sale, or Other Asset Transfers

If Meetup is involved in a merger, acquisition, financing, reorganization, bankruptcy, or sale of our assets, information about you may be shared, sold, or transferred as part of that transaction. We may also share information about you with current or future corporate parents, subsidiaries, or affiliates.

3.6 Other Situations

We may share de-identified or aggregated information about you. We may also share information about you with your consent or at your direction.

## 4\. Additional Details

Summary:

  * We may allow others to use technologies that collect information about you to provide analytic services, and to serve ads for Meetup. You may be able to opt out of the collection or use of this information.
  * You can review and change information about you in your account on the Platform, or deactivate your account, but we may retain certain information.
  * You may opt out of receiving Meetup’s promotional messages, but you may still receive other communications.
  * Meetup is based in and governed by U.S. law, and you consent to processing, transfer, and storage of information in and to the U.S. and other countries.
  * We cannot guarantee the absolute security of information about you.
  * This Privacy Policy is periodically updated, and does not apply to third parties.
  * If you have any questions, you can contact us at [privacy@meetup.com](mailto:privacy@meetup.com). 

4.1 Analytics and Advertising Services Provided by Others

We may allow others to use cookies, web beacons, device identifiers, and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Platform and other websites and online services. See our [Cookie Policy](https://www.meetup.com/cookie_policy/) for details about these technologies and the information that they collect, use, or share, including how you may be able to control these services or opt out. 

4.2 Your Choices: Account Information

You may update or correct the account information that you have provided to Meetup by editing your account settings or by sending an email to [support@meetup.com](mailto:support@meetup.com). You may deactivate your account by editing your account settings or by sending an email to [support@meetup.com](mailto:support@meetup.com). Meetup may retain certain information as needed to comply with our legal obligations or for legitimate business purposes, such as to resolve disputes and enforce our legal rights. We may also retain cached or archived copies of information about you for a certain period of time. 

4.3 Your Choices: Location Information

When you first access the Platform, you may be asked to consent to our collection of location information. If you do not consent to this collection, you may not be able to use our mobile application. You can stop the collection of location information at any time from a particular device by changing the settings on that device, but note that our Platform or its features may no longer function properly if you do.

4.4 Your Choices: Cookies

Most devices and web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you may be able to remove or reject browser cookies. You can learn more about cookies, including how to block cookies, by visiting [allaboutcookies.org](http://allaboutcookies.org/). Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Platform. 

4.5 Your Choices: Promotional Communications

You may opt out of receiving promotional messages from Meetup by following the instructions in those messages or by adjusting the communication preferences that you indicate in your account. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional messages, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.

4.6 Transfer of Information to the U.S. and Other Countries

Meetup is based in the United States and the information we collect is governed by U.S. law. By accessing or using the Platform or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to the processing, transfer, and storage of information in and to the U.S. and other countries, where you may not have the same rights and protections as you do under local law.

4.7 Security

We employ measures designed to protect information about you, both during transmission and once we receive it. For example, we use firewalls designed to protect against intruders and test for network vulnerabilities. However, no method of transmission over the internet or method of electronic storage is completely secure.

4.8 Policy Scope

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information you provide to third parties, such as members of Meetup, and others with whom you may share information about you. Our Platform may direct you to a third-party service or a portion of our Platform controlled by a third party (typically through the use of a frame or pop-up window separate from other content on our Platform). Disclosure of information to these third parties is subject to the relevant third party’s privacy policy. We are not responsible for the third-party privacy policy or content, even if we link to those services from our Platform.

4.9 Revisions to this Policy

We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will provide notice to you by publishing the most current version and revising the date at the top of this page. If we make any material change to this policy, we will provide additional notice to you, such as by sending you an email or displaying a prominent notice on our Platform. By continuing to use the Platform after any changes come into effect, the revised Privacy Policy applies to you.

4.10 Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@meetup.com](mailto:privacy@meetup.com).
